<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Notes</title>
    <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phobos &amp; Deimos</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/phobos_deimos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/phobos_deimos/</guid>
      <description>Apparent size # https://photojournal.jpl.nasa.gov/catalog/PIA17351&#xA;This illustration provides a comparison for how big the moons of Mars appear to be, as seen from the surface of Mars, in relation to the size that Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon appears to be when seen from the surface of Earth. Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon actually has a diameter more than 100 times greater than the larger Martian moon, Phobos. However, the Martian moons orbit much closer to their planet than the distance between Earth and Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noctis Labyrinthus</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/noctis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/noctis/</guid>
      <description>Sources: # Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noctis_Labyrinthus Local Geology # USGS Geological map data # From Wikipedia https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ore_resources_on_Mars:&#xA;The abundance of volcanic features together with widespread cratering are strong evidence for a variety of ores.&#xA;Source: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/239594538_Potential_martian_mineral_resources_Mechanisms_and_terrestrial_analogues&#xA;The USGS geological map shows several different regions in the Noctis area:&#xA;Noctis seems to be a primarily volcanic region, with compression features, graben and other types of folds and cracks due to tectonical stress, a huge crater (Oudemans) with moraines and landslides and smaller craters nearby, plus signs of eolic and fluvial erosion, so probably also some sedimentary rocks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Atlas of Mars</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/cloud_atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/cloud_atlas/</guid>
      <description>Alternative visualization of the Cloud Atlas of Mars database, presented at the Europlanet Science Congress (EPSC) 2024 in Berlin by Daniela Tirsch of DLR.&#xA;The images in the Cloud Atlas have been captured by the High Resolution Stereo Camera (HRSC) instrument, which is on board the European Space Agency (ESA) Mars Express spacecraft.&#xA;Source data from https://hrscteam.dlr.de/public/data.php&#xA;Index: # Cloud Types Orographic Clouds Twilight Clouds Synoptic Phenomena Dust Lifting Events Locations # Click on a marker to see the corresponding picture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;All the conditions for murder are met&#34;: the strange history of a cosmonaut&#39;s quote</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/blog/conditions-for-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/blog/conditions-for-murder/</guid>
      <description>All the conditions necessary for murder are met if you shut two men in a cabin measuring 18 feet by 20 and leave them together for two months.&#xA;When discussing the living conditions of astronauts, this short, dark quote by Valery Ryumin (Валерий Викторович Рюмин) is often one of the opening lines. It is sure a clear hint that being an astronaut wasn&amp;rsquo;t in fact such a glamourous experience, especially during mission that lasted several weeks or months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>Bookshelf # Collection of books, movies and short stories I&amp;rsquo;ve come across, in no particular order.&#xA;To read # &amp;ldquo;The Machine Stops&amp;rdquo;, by Edward Morgan Foster &amp;ldquo;A Meeting with Medusa&amp;rdquo;, by Arthur C. Clarke Followed by &amp;ldquo;The Medusa Chronicles&amp;rdquo;, by Stephen Baxter and Alastair Reynolds &amp;ldquo;The Master Key&amp;rdquo;, by Lyman Frank Baum &amp;ldquo;The invisible life of Addie LaRue&amp;rdquo;, by Victoria E. Schwab &amp;ldquo;Lanark: a life in four books&amp;rdquo;, by Alasdair Gray &amp;ldquo;The dream with no dreamer&amp;rdquo;, by Evan Forman &amp;ldquo;The Lotus Caves&amp;rdquo; by John Christopher (Sam Youd) &amp;ldquo;Walkaway&amp;rdquo;, by Cory Doctorow &amp;ldquo;The Metamorphosis of Prime Intellect&amp;rdquo;, by Roger Williams &amp;ldquo;We Are Legion (We Are Bob)&amp;rdquo;, by Dennis E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceres</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/40-asteroid-belt/10_ceres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/40-asteroid-belt/10_ceres/</guid>
      <description>Ceres is a dwarf planet in the middle main asteroid belt between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter, the only dwarf planet to be found inside Neptune&amp;rsquo;s orbit.&#xA;Ceres is the largest body in the asteroid belt, but is still fairly small. For comparison, even though Ceres comprises 25% of the asteroid belt&amp;rsquo;s total mass, Pluto is still 14 times more massive.&#xA;Main resources # Webpages # NASA&amp;rsquo;s Ceres page: https://science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/0-planetary-science/comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/0-planetary-science/comparisons/</guid>
      <description>https://what-if.xkcd.com/30/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europa</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/60-jupiter/europa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/60-jupiter/europa/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Europa_(moon)&#xA;Maps # Europa has a geological map and defined quadrangles.&#xA;USGS Map # https://pubs.usgs.gov/imap/i2757/&#xA;NOTES ON BASE This sheet is one in a series of maps of the Galilean satellites of Jupiter at a nominal scale of 1:15,000,000. This series is based on data from the Galileo Orbiter Solid-State Imaging (SSI) camera and the Voyager 1 and 2 spacecraft.&#xA;PROJECTION Mercator and Polar Stereographic projections used for this map of Europa are based on a sphere having a radius of 1,562.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flowers for Algernon</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/keyes-flowers-for-algernon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/keyes-flowers-for-algernon/</guid>
      <description>progris riport 1-martch 5, 1965&#xA;Dr. Strauss says I shud rite down what I think and evrey thing that happins to me from now on, I dont know why but he says its importint so they will see if they will use me. I hope they use me. Miss Kinnian says maybe they can make me smart. I want to be smart. My name is Charlie Gordon. I am 37 years old.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Story of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/chiang-story-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/chiang-story-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Your father is about to ask me the question. This is the most important moment in our lives, and I want to pay attention, note every detail. Your dad and I have just come back from an evening out, dinner and a show; it&#39;s after midnight. We came out onto the patio to look at the full moon; then I told your dad I wanted to dance, so he humors me and now we&#39;re slow-dancing, a pair of thirtysomethings swaying back and forth in the moon-light like kids.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superiority</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-superiority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-superiority/</guid>
      <description>IN MAKING THIS STATEMENT—which I do of my own free will—I wish first to make it perfectly clear that I am not in any way trying to gain sympathy, nor do I expect any mitigation of whatever sentence the Court may pronounce. I am writing this in an attempt to refute some of the lying reports broadcast over the prison radio and published in the papers I have been allowed to see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraforming Planets</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/0-planetary-science/terraforming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/0-planetary-science/terraforming/</guid>
      <description>https://www.universetoday.com/121140/could-we-terraform-the-moon/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/128711/how-do-we-terraform-ceres/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/139725/uh-oh-mars-doesnt-have-enough-carbon-dioxide-to-be-terraformed/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/139481/could-cyanobacteria-help-to-terraform-mars/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/134230/future-space-colonization-terraforming-space-habitats/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/128531/terraform-mercury/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/128532/terraform-saturns-moons/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/128530/how-do-we-terraform-jupiters-moons/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/113346/how-do-we-terraform-mars/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/113412/how-do-we-terraform-venus/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/127311/guide-to-terraforming/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/91920/should-we-terraform-mars/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/15795/podcast-humans-to-mars-part-3-terraforming-mars/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/9730/zubrin-on-terraforming-mars/&#xA;https://www.universetoday.com/9383/terraforming-mars-one-piece-at-a-time/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/guin-the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/guin-the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</guid>
      <description>In the temperate and tropical regions where it appears that hominids evolved into human beings, the principal food of the species was vegetable. Sixty-five to eighty percent of what human beings ate in those regions in Paleolithic, Neolithic, and prehistoric times was gathered; only in the extreme Arctic was meat the staple food. The mammoth hunters spectacularly occupy the cave wall and the mind, but what we actually did to stay alive and fat was gather seeds, roots, sprouts, shoots, leaves, nuts, berries, fruits, and grains, adding bugs and mollusks and netting or snaring birds, fish, rats, rabbits, and other tuskless small fry to up the protein.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Technological Singularity</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/vinge-the-coming-technological-singularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/vinge-the-coming-technological-singularity/</guid>
      <description>The Coming Technological Singularity:&#xA;How to Survive in the Post-Human Era&#xA;Vernor Vinge&#xA;Department of Mathematical Sciences&#xA;San Diego State University&#xA;(c) 1993 by Vernor Vinge&#xA;(Verbatim copying/translation and distribution of this entire article is permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.)&#xA;This article was for the VISION-21 Symposium sponsored by NASA Lewis Research Center and the Ohio Aerospace Institute, March 30-31, 1993. It is also retrievable from the NASA technical reports server as part of NASA CP-10129.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Creatures That Time Forgot (or &#34;Frost and Fire&#34;)</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-the-creatures-that-time-forgot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-the-creatures-that-time-forgot/</guid>
      <description>During the night, Sim was born. He lay wailing upon the cold cave stones. His blood beat through him a thousand pulses each minute. He grew, steadily.&#xA;Into his mouth his mother with feverish hands put the food. The nightmare of living was begun. Almost instantly at birth his eyes grew alert, and then, without half understanding why, filled with bright, insistent terror. He gagged upon the food, choked and wailed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Minority Report</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/dick-minority-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/dick-minority-report/</guid>
      <description>I The first thought that Anderton had when he saw the young man was: I&#39;m getting bald. Bald and fat and old. But he didn&#39;t say it aloud. Instead, he pushed back his chair, got to his feet, and came resolutely around the side of his desk, his right hand rigidly extended. Smiling with forced amiability, he shook hands with the young man. “Witwer?” he asked, managing to make this query sound gracious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Night (or &#34;Ice Cream on a Summer&#39;s Evening&#34;)</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-the-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-the-night/</guid>
      <description>Night is more than darkness; it is life and death and all things beyond our feeble knowledges&#xA;You are a child in a small town. You are, to be exact, eight years old, and it is growing late at night. Late, for you, accustomed to bedding in at nine or nine-thirty; once in a while perhaps begging Mom or Dad to let you stay up later to hear Sam and Henry on that strange radio that was popular in this year of 1927.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sentinel</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-the-sentinel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-the-sentinel/</guid>
      <description>The next time you see the full moon high in the south, look carefully at its right-hand edge and let your eye travel upward along the curve of the disk. Round about two o’clock you will notice a small, dark oval: anyone with normal eyesight can find it quite easily. It is the great walled plain, one of the finest on the Moon, known as the Mare Crisium-the Sea of Crises.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Star</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-the-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/clarke-the-star/</guid>
      <description>It is three thousand light-years to the Vatican. Once, I believed that space could have no power over faith, just as I believed the heavens declared the glory of God’s handwork. Now I have seen that handiwork, and my faith is sorely troubled. I stare at the crucifix that hangs on the cabin wall above the Mark VI Computer, and for the first time in my life I wonder if it is no more than an empty symbol.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There Will Come Soft Rains</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-there-will-come-soft-rains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/bradbury-there-will-come-soft-rains/</guid>
      <description>In the living room the voice-clock sang, Tick-tock, seven o&#39;clock, time to get up, time to get up, seven o&#39;clock! as if it were afraid nobody would. The morning house lay empty. The clock ticked on, repeating and repeating its sounds into the emptiness. Seven-nine, breakfast time, seven-nine!&#xA;In the kitchen the breakfast stove gave a hissing sigh and ejected from its warm interior eight pieces of perfectly browned toast, eight eggs sunnyside up, sixteen slices of bacon, two coffees, and two cool glasses of milk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titan</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/70-saturn/titan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/70-saturn/titan/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Titan_(moon)&#xA;Maps # Quadrangles # Titan&amp;rsquo;s quadrangles haven&amp;rsquo;t been defined at the time of writing. We can assume that they should be named &amp;ldquo;St&amp;rdquo; can be inferred from the other jovian and saturnian moons such as Europa (Je), Ganymede (Jg), Enceladus (Se)&amp;hellip; So Titan should be St.&#xA;Regarding the quadrangles definition, I overlapped the traditional division into 15 quadrangles of the Jovian moons (and other moons/small planets) found here: https://ntrs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Can Remember It For You Wholesale</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/dick-we-can-remember-for-you-wholesale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/library/dick-we-can-remember-for-you-wholesale/</guid>
      <description>HE AWOKE—and wanted Mars. The valleys, he thought. What would it be like to trudge among them? Great and greater yet: the dream grew as he became fully conscious, the dream and the yearning. He could almost feel the enveloping presence of the other world, which only Government agents and high officials had seen. A clerk like himself? Not likely. &#34;Are you getting up or not?&#34; his wife Kirsten asked drowsily, with her usual hint of fierce crossness.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
