<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mars on Notes</title>
    <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mars on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phobos &amp; Deimos</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/phobos_deimos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/phobos_deimos/</guid>
      <description>Apparent size # https://photojournal.jpl.nasa.gov/catalog/PIA17351&#xA;This illustration provides a comparison for how big the moons of Mars appear to be, as seen from the surface of Mars, in relation to the size that Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon appears to be when seen from the surface of Earth. Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon actually has a diameter more than 100 times greater than the larger Martian moon, Phobos. However, the Martian moons orbit much closer to their planet than the distance between Earth and Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noctis Labyrinthus</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/noctis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/noctis/</guid>
      <description>Sources: # Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noctis_Labyrinthus Local Geology # USGS Geological map data # From Wikipedia https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ore_resources_on_Mars:&#xA;The abundance of volcanic features together with widespread cratering are strong evidence for a variety of ores.&#xA;Source: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/239594538_Potential_martian_mineral_resources_Mechanisms_and_terrestrial_analogues&#xA;The USGS geological map shows several different regions in the Noctis area:&#xA;Noctis seems to be a primarily volcanic region, with compression features, graben and other types of folds and cracks due to tectonical stress, a huge crater (Oudemans) with moraines and landslides and smaller craters nearby, plus signs of eolic and fluvial erosion, so probably also some sedimentary rocks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Atlas of Mars</title>
      <link>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/cloud_atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenjiezan.github.io/site/docs/solar-system/50-mars/cloud_atlas/</guid>
      <description>Alternative visualization of the Cloud Atlas of Mars database, presented at the Europlanet Science Congress (EPSC) 2024 in Berlin by Daniela Tirsch of DLR.&#xA;The images in the Cloud Atlas have been captured by the High Resolution Stereo Camera (HRSC) instrument, which is on board the European Space Agency (ESA) Mars Express spacecraft.&#xA;Source data from https://hrscteam.dlr.de/public/data.php&#xA;Index: # Cloud Types Orographic Clouds Twilight Clouds Synoptic Phenomena Dust Lifting Events Locations # Click on a marker to see the corresponding picture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
